<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Manisha's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://manisha11.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://manisha11.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-20T17:55:57+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://manisha11.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Manisha]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Install LAMP Stack on Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://manisha11.github.io/blog/2013/06/20/how-to-install-lamp-stack-on-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T13:23:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://manisha11.github.io/blog/2013/06/20/how-to-install-lamp-stack-on-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LAMP stack is a group of open source software used to get web servers up and running.
The acronym stands for Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP.</p>

<p>Set Up:&ndash;</p>

<p>Step One—Install Apache
Apache is a free open source software which runs over 50% of the world’s web servers.</p>

<p>To install apache, open terminal and type in these commands:</p>

<p>[1]</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install apache2
</code></pre>

<p>That’s it. To check if Apache is installed, direct your browser to your server’s IP (eg. <a href="http://12.34.56.786">http://12.34.56.786</a>).The page should display the words &ldquo;Success&rdquo;</p>

<p>How to Find your Server’s IP address:&ndash;
To reveal your server&rsquo;s IP address type in the following command.</p>

<p>[2]</p>

<pre><code>ifconfig eth0|grep inet|awk '{print $2}'
</code></pre>

<p>Step Two—Install MySQL</p>

<p>MySQL is a powerful database management system used for organizing and retrieving data</p>

<p>To install MySQL, open terminal and type in these commands:</p>

<p>[3]</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install mysql-server libapache2-mod-auth-mysql php5-mysql
</code></pre>

<p>Once you have installed MySQL, we should activate it with this command:</p>

<p>[4]</p>

<pre><code>sudo mysql_install_db
</code></pre>

<p>Finish up by running the MySQL set up script:</p>

<p>[5]</p>

<pre><code>sudo /usr/bin/mysql_secure_installation
</code></pre>

<p>The prompt will ask for the current root password.</p>

<p>Type it in.</p>

<p>[6]</p>

<pre><code>Enter current password for root (enter for none): 
OK, successfully used password, moving on...
</code></pre>

<p>Then the prompt will ask you if you want to change the root password. Go ahead and choose N and move on to the next steps.</p>

<p>[7]
   It’s easiest just to say Yes to all the options. At        <br/>
   the end MySQL will reload and implement the new changes.</p>

<p>   By default, a MySQL installation has an anonymous user,     allowing anyone
   to log into MySQL without having to have a user account created for
   them.  This is intended only for testing, and to make the  installation
   go a bit smoother.  You should remove them before moving into a
   production environment.</p>

<pre><code>Remove anonymous users? [Y/n]  y                                          
... Success!

Normally, root should only be allowed to connect from '  'localhost'.  This
ensures that someone cannot guess at the root password from the network.

Disallow root login remotely? [Y/n] y
... Success!

By default, MySQL comes with a database named 'test' that  anyone can
access.  This is also intended only for testing, and should be removed
before moving into a production environment.

Remove test database and access to it? [Y/n] y
- Dropping test database...
 ... Success!
- Removing privileges on test database...
 ... Success!

 Reloading the privilege tables will ensure that all  changes made so far
 will take effect immediately.

 Reload privilege tables now? [Y/n] y
 .. Success!
</code></pre>

<p>Step Three—Install PHP:
PHP is an open source web scripting language that is widely use to build dynamic webpages.</p>

<p>To install PHP, open terminal and type in this command.</p>

<p>[7]</p>

<pre><code>sudo apt-get install php5 libapache2-mod-php5 php5-mcrypt
</code></pre>

<p>It may also be useful to add php to the directory index, to serve the relevant php index files:</p>

<p>[8]</p>

<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/apache2/mods-enabled/dir.conf
</code></pre>

<p>Add index.php to the beginning of index files.Now the page should now look like this:
[9]</p>

<pre><code>&lt;IfModule mod_dir.c&gt;

      DirectoryIndex index.php index.html index.cgi  index.pl index.php index.xhtml index.htm

&lt;/IfModule&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>PHP Modules</p>

<p>PHP also has a variety of useful libraries and modules that you can add onto your virtual server. You can see the libraries that are available.
[10]</p>

<pre><code> apt-cache search php5-
</code></pre>

<p>Terminal will then display the list of possible modules. The beginning looks like this:</p>

<p>[11]</p>

<pre><code> php5-cgi - server-side, HTML-embedded scripting language (CGI binary)
 php5-cli - command-line interpreter for the php5 scripting language
 php5-common - Common files for packages built from the php5 source
 php5-curl - CURL module for php5
 php5-dbg - Debug symbols for PHP5
 php5-dev - Files for PHP5 module development
 php5-gd - GD module for php5
 php5-gmp - GMP module for php5
 php5-ldap - LDAP module for php5
 php5-mysql - MySQL module for php5
 php5-odbc - ODBC module for php5
 php5-pgsql - PostgreSQL module for php5
 php5-pspell - pspell module for php5
 php5-recode - recode module for php5
 php5-snmp - SNMP module for php5
 php5-sqlite - SQLite module for php5
 php5-tidy - tidy module for php5
 php5-xmlrpc - XML-RPC module for php5
 php5-xsl - XSL module for php5
 php5-adodb - Extension optimising the ADOdb database  abstraction library
 php5-auth-pam - A PHP5 extension for PAM authentication
</code></pre>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p>Once you decide to install the module, type:</p>

<p>[11]</p>

<pre><code> sudo apt-get install name of the module
</code></pre>

<p>You can install multiple libraries at once by separating the name of each module with a space.</p>

<p>NOW THE LAMP STACK IS SUCCESSFULLY INSTALLED.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ANDROID]]></title>
    <link href="http://manisha11.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/android/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T15:06:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://manisha11.github.io/blog/2013/06/06/android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Android is a Linux-based operating system designed primarily for touchscreen mobile devices such as smartphones and tablet computers. Initially developed by Android, Inc., which Google backed financially and later bought in 2005, Android was unveiled in 2007 along with the founding of the Open Handset Alliance: a consortium of hardware, software, and telecommunication companies devoted to advancing open standards for mobile devices. The first Android-powered phone was sold in October 2008.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.animoca.com/en/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/android-connected-fragmentation.jpg"></p>

<p>These factors have contributed towards making Android the world&rsquo;s most widely used smartphone platform,overtaking Symbian in the fourth quarter of 2010, and the software of choice for technology companies who require a low-cost, customizable, lightweight operating system for high tech devices without developing one from scratch. As a result, despite being primarily designed for phones and tablets, it has seen additional applications on televisions, games consoles, digital cameras and other electronics. Android&rsquo;s open nature has further encouraged a large community of developers and enthusiasts to use the open source code as a foundation for community-driven projects, which add new features for advanced users or bring Android to devices which were officially released running other operating systems.</p>

<p>The open and customizable nature of Android allows it to be used on other electronics, including laptops and netbooks, smartbooks smart TVs (Google TV) and cameras (Nikon Coolpix S800c and Galaxy Camera). In addition, the Android operating system has seen applications on smart glasses (Google Glass), wristwatches, headphones, car CD and DVD players, mirrors, portable media players and landlines and Voice over IP phones. Ouya, an upcoming videogames console running Android, became one of the most successful Kickstarter campaigns, crowdfunding US$8.5m for its development,and was later followed by other Android-based video games consoles such as Project Shield from Nvidia.</p>

<p>Starts your android tutorial with this</p>

<p>VIDEO Link:&ndash; <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lESZqCflB0o">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lESZqCflB0o</a></p>

<p>In 2011, Google demonstrated &ldquo;Android@Home&rdquo;, a new home automaton technology which uses Android to control a range of household devices including light switches, power sockets and thermostats. Prototype light bulbs were announced that could be controlled from an Android phone or tablet, but Android head Andy Rubin was cautious to note that &ldquo;turning a lightbulb on and off is nothing new,&rdquo; pointing to numerous failed home automation services. Google, he said, was thinking more ambitiously and the intention was to use their position as a cloud services provider to bring Google products into customers&#8217; homes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
